<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<posts>
  <row Id="25" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="1443907" CreationDate="2008-08-01T12:13:50.207" Score="150" ViewCount="12424" Body="&lt;p&gt;I'm having issues getting the C sockets API to work properly in &lt;code&gt;C++&lt;/code&gt; on &lt;code&gt;z/OS&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although I am including &lt;code&gt;sys/socket.h&lt;/code&gt;, I still get &lt;strong&gt;compile time errors&lt;/strong&gt; telling me that &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;AF_INET&lt;/code&gt; is not defined&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Am I missing something obvious, or is this related to the fact that being on &lt;code&gt;z/OS&lt;/code&gt; makes my problems much more complicated?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt; : Upon further investigation, I discovered that there is an &lt;code&gt;#ifdef&lt;/code&gt; that I'm hitting. Apparently &lt;code&gt;z/OS&lt;/code&gt; isn't happy unless I define which &quot;type&quot; of sockets I'm using with:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#define _OE_SOCKETS&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now, I personally have no idea what this &lt;code&gt;_OE_SOCKETS&lt;/code&gt; is actually for, so if any &lt;code&gt;z/OS&lt;/code&gt; sockets programmers are out there (all 3 of you), perhaps you could give me a rundown of how this all works?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Test App&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#include &amp;lt;sys/socket.h&amp;gt;&#xA;&#xA;int main()&#xA;{&#xA;    return AF_INET;&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compile/Link Output:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cxx -Wc,xplink -Wl,xplink -o inet_test inet.C&#xA;&#xA;&quot;./inet.C&quot;, line 5.16: CCN5274 (S) The name lookup for &quot;AF_INET&quot; did not find a declaration.&#xA;CCN0797(I) Compilation failed for file ./inet.C. Object file not created.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A check of sys/sockets.h does include the definition I need, and as far as I can tell, it is not being blocked by any &lt;code&gt;#ifdef&lt;/code&gt; statements.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have however noticed it contains the following:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#ifdef __cplusplus&#xA;  extern &quot;C&quot; {&#xA;#endif&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;which encapsulates basically the whole file? Not sure if it matters.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="23" LastEditorUserId="11383441" LastEditorDisplayName="user5857081" LastEditDate="2019-12-13T10:19:06.430" LastActivityDate="2019-12-13T10:19:06.430" Title="How to use the C socket API in C++ on z/OS" Tags="&lt;c++&gt;&lt;c&gt;&lt;sockets&gt;&lt;mainframe&gt;&lt;zos&gt;" AnswerCount="9" CommentCount="0" FavoriteCount="8" />
  <row Id="39" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="45" CreationDate="2008-08-01T12:43:11.503" Score="95" ViewCount="6608" Body="&lt;p&gt;I am aware that in &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/.NET_Framework&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;.NET&lt;/a&gt; there are three timer types (see &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/magazine/cc164015.aspx&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Comparing the Timer Classes in the .NET Framework Class Library&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;). I have chosen a threaded timer as the other types can drift if the main thread is busy, and I need this to be reliable.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The way this timer works in the control of the timer is put on another thread so it can always tick along with the work begin completed on the parent thread when it is not busy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The issue with this timer in a console application is that while the timer is ticking along on another thread the main thread is not doing anything to the application closes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I tried adding a &lt;code&gt;while true&lt;/code&gt; loop, but then the main thread is too busy when the timer does go off.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="33" LastEditorUserId="567854" LastEditorDisplayName="Jim Anderson" LastEditDate="2019-01-20T13:50:37.530" LastActivityDate="2019-12-29T14:13:55.290" Title="Reliable timer in a console application" Tags="&lt;c#&gt;&lt;.net&gt;&lt;vb.net&gt;&lt;timer&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="0" FavoriteCount="3" />
  <row Id="98" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="88" CreationDate="2008-08-01T14:53:47.497" Score="55" Body="&lt;p&gt;Maybe. But you have bigger problems. &lt;code&gt;gettimeofday()&lt;/code&gt; can result in incorrect timings if there are processes on your system that change the timer (ie, ntpd). On a &quot;normal&quot; linux, though, I believe the resolution of &lt;code&gt;gettimeofday()&lt;/code&gt; is 10us. It can jump forward and backward and time, consequently, based on the processes running on your system. This effectively makes the answer to your question no.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You should look into &lt;code&gt;clock_gettime(CLOCK_MONOTONIC)&lt;/code&gt; for timing intervals. It suffers from several less issues due to things like multi-core systems and external clock settings.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also, look into the &lt;code&gt;clock_getres()&lt;/code&gt; function.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="2089740" LastEditorUserId="967315" LastEditorDisplayName="lbrandy" LastEditDate="2012-10-14T12:28:51.043" LastActivityDate="2012-10-14T12:28:51.043" CommentCount="5" />
  <row Id="108" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="111" CreationDate="2008-08-01T15:22:29.467" Score="44" ViewCount="15337" Body="&lt;p&gt;I've been using &lt;a href=&quot;http://tortoisesvn.tigris.org/&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;TortoiseSVN &lt;/a&gt; in a Windows environment for quite some time.  It seems very feature-complete and nicely integrated into the Windows shell, and more importantly, it's fairly painless to teach to colleagues with little or no experience with source control.  &lt;strong&gt;However&lt;/strong&gt;, since we have moved to Windows Vista 64bit, Tortoise has been very buggy and has seemed to cause lots of explorer.exe abnormalities and crashes.  This has happened both with older versions of the software and the latest version (1.5.1 build 13563).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was curious if anyone has suggestions for other Subversion clients that will run on Windows (specifically Vista 64bit).  Developers here use a variety of text editors so using Visual Studio or Dreamweaver for SVN is not ideal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have heard great things about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zennaware.com/cornerstone/&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Cornerstone&lt;/a&gt;, and would love something similar for Windows if it exists.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I'm correlating the Vista/explorer problems with Tortoise because they normally occur when I'm using the functionality in Tortoise.  Sometimes bringing up the &quot;merge&quot; screen will cause the GUI to start acting very strange and eventually hang or crash.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I did not see 1.5.2 -- I'm installing now, maybe that will fix some of my issues.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="72" LastEditorUserId="1288" LastEditorDisplayName="Adam Mitz" LastEditDate="2011-11-20T13:46:24.733" LastActivityDate="2018-05-10T00:13:14.383" Title="Best Subversion clients for Windows Vista (64bit)" Tags="&lt;windows&gt;&lt;svn&gt;&lt;64-bit&gt;" AnswerCount="8" CommentCount="0" FavoriteCount="2" ClosedDate="2012-08-15T19:45:13.350" />
  <row Id="111" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="108" CreationDate="2008-08-01T15:27:23.093" Score="38" Body="&lt;p&gt;I have been using the 64Bit version of TortoiseSVN for ages and I have never had issues with it on Windows 64Bit or Vista 64Bit. I am currently not aware of any other similiar SVN clients that do work on Vista. Is it possible the problem could lie within the configuration of TortoiseSVN or even the installation of Vista? Is the problem occurring on Vista native or SP 1?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="146270" OwnerDisplayName="Diago" LastActivityDate="2008-08-01T15:27:23.093" CommentCount="2" />
  <row Id="161" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="104" CreationDate="2008-08-01T17:57:14.117" Score="19" Body="&lt;p&gt;I would define memory leaks as an object not freeing up all the memory allocated after it has completed. I have found this can happen in your application if you are using Windows API and COM (i.e. unmanaged code that has a bug in it or is not being managed correctly), in the framework and in third party components. I have also found not tiding up after using certain objects like pens can cause the issue.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I personally have suffered Out of Memory Exceptions which can be caused but are not exclusive to memory leaks in dot net applications. (OOM can also come from pinning see &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.msdn.com/yunjin/archive/2004/01/27/63642.aspx&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Pinning Artical&lt;/a&gt;). If you are not getting OOM errors or need to confirm if it is a memory leak causing it then the only way is to profile your application.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I would also try and ensure the following:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a) Everything that implements Idisposable is disposed either using a finally block or the using statement these include brushes, pens etc.(some people argue to set everything to nothing in addition) &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;b)Anything that has a close method is closed again using finally or the using statement (although I have found using does not always close depending if you declared the object outside the using statement)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;c)If you are using unmanaged code/windows API's that these are dealt with correctly after. (some have clean up methods to release resources)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hope this helps.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="33" LastActivityDate="2008-08-01T17:57:14.117" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="194" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="197" CreationDate="2008-08-01T19:26:37.883" Score="35" ViewCount="3853" Body="&lt;p&gt;Yes, I know.  The existence of a running copy of &lt;code&gt;SQL Server 6.5&lt;/code&gt; in 2008 is absurd.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That stipulated, what is the best way to migrate from &lt;code&gt;6.5&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;2005&lt;/code&gt;?  Is there any direct path?  Most of the documentation I've found deals with upgrading &lt;code&gt;6.5&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;7&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Should I forget about the native &lt;code&gt;SQL Server&lt;/code&gt; upgrade utilities, script out all of the objects and data, and try to recreate from scratch?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was going to attempt the upgrade this weekend, but server issues pushed it back till next.  So, any ideas would be welcomed during the course of the week.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update.  This is how I ended up doing it:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Back up the database in question and Master on &lt;code&gt;6.5&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Execute &lt;code&gt;SQL Server 2000&lt;/code&gt;'s &lt;code&gt;instcat.sql&lt;/code&gt; against &lt;code&gt;6.5&lt;/code&gt;'s Master.  This allows &lt;code&gt;SQL Server 2000&lt;/code&gt;'s OLEDB provider to connect to &lt;code&gt;6.5&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use &lt;code&gt;SQL Server 2000&lt;/code&gt;'s standalone &lt;code&gt;&quot;Import and Export Data&quot;&lt;/code&gt; to create a DTS package, using &lt;code&gt;OLEDB&lt;/code&gt; to connect to 6.5.  This successfully copied all &lt;code&gt;6.5&lt;/code&gt;'s tables to a new &lt;code&gt;2005&lt;/code&gt; database (also using &lt;code&gt;OLEDB&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use &lt;code&gt;6.5&lt;/code&gt;'s Enterprise Manager to script out all of the database's indexes and triggers to a .sql file.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Execute that .sql file against the new copy of the database, in 2005's Management Studio.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use 6.5's Enterprise Manager to script out all of the stored procedures.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Execute that &lt;code&gt;.sql&lt;/code&gt; file against the &lt;code&gt;2005&lt;/code&gt; database.  Several dozen sprocs had issues making them incompatible with &lt;code&gt;2005&lt;/code&gt;.  Mainly &lt;code&gt;non-ANSI joins&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;quoted identifier issues&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Corrected all of those issues and re-executed the &lt;code&gt;.sql&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Recreated the &lt;code&gt;6.5&lt;/code&gt;'s logins in &lt;code&gt;2005&lt;/code&gt; and gave them appropriate permissions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There was a bit of rinse/repeat when correcting the stored procedures (there were hundreds of them to correct), but the upgrade went great otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Being able to use Management Studio instead of &lt;code&gt;Query Analyzer&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Enterprise Manager 6.5&lt;/code&gt; is such an amazing difference.  A few report queries that took 20-30 seconds on the &lt;code&gt;6.5 database&lt;/code&gt; are now running in 1-2 seconds, without any modification, new indexes, or anything.  I didn't expect that kind of immediate improvement.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="60" LastEditorUserId="165216" LastEditorDisplayName="Nigel Campbell" LastEditDate="2012-06-12T05:35:46.927" LastActivityDate="2017-01-17T09:38:49.320" Title="Upgrading SQL Server 6.5" Tags="&lt;sql-server&gt;&lt;migration&gt;" AnswerCount="4" CommentCount="0" FavoriteCount="2" />
  <row Id="330" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="332" CreationDate="2008-08-02T02:51:36.470" Score="52" ViewCount="4146" Body="&lt;p&gt;I am working on a collection of classes used for video playback and recording. I have one main class which acts like the public interface, with methods like &lt;code&gt;play()&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;stop()&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;pause()&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;record()&lt;/code&gt; etc... Then I have workhorse classes which do the video decoding and video encoding. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I just learned about the existence of nested classes in C++, and I'm curious to know what programmers think about using them. I am a little wary and not really sure what the benefits/drawbacks are, but they seem (according to the book I'm reading) to be used in cases such as mine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The book suggests that in a scenario like mine, a good solution would be to nest the workhorse classes inside the interface class, so there are no separate files for classes the client is not meant to use, and to avoid any possible naming conflicts? I don't know about these justifications. Nested classes are a new concept to me. Just want to see what programmers think about the issue.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="63" LastEditorUserId="204623" LastEditorDisplayName="Jason Etheridge" LastEditDate="2012-09-03T08:53:51.277" LastActivityDate="2013-03-27T20:24:09.153" Title="Should I use nested classes in this case?" Tags="&lt;c++&gt;&lt;oop&gt;&lt;class&gt;&lt;nested-class&gt;" AnswerCount="10" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="451" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="371" CreationDate="2008-08-02T13:45:57.197" Score="13" Body="&lt;p&gt;Yahoo uses a method called Sender ID, which can be configured at &lt;a href=&quot;http://old.openspf.org/wizard.html?mydomain=stackoverflow.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;The SPF Setup Wizard&lt;/a&gt; and entered in to your DNS.  Also one of the important ones for Exchange, Hotmail, AOL, Yahoo, and others is to have a Reverse DNS for your domain.  Those will knock out most of the issues.  However you can never prevent a person intentionally blocking your or custom rules.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="17" LastEditorUserId="246246" LastEditDate="2017-04-20T16:17:40.470" LastActivityDate="2017-04-20T16:17:40.470" CommentCount="1" />
  <row Id="562" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2008-08-02T21:39:11.733" Score="43" ViewCount="3569" Body="&lt;p&gt;Uploading my first decently sized web app to my shared host provided me with a fresh set of challenges, by which I mean, sleepless nights. The issue was that I had most certainly not developed my application for medium trust (or had any clue what that was.) &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I mitigated all of the issues, save one. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had written an installer for the admin to be able to specify their connection string and other preferences, but I cannot find a way to write to a web.config in medium trust. Does anyone have a solution, or should I just be putting preferences in another file?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerDisplayName="Aaron" LastEditorUserId="567854" LastEditorDisplayName="Gulzar" LastEditDate="2019-01-20T13:48:44.203" LastActivityDate="2019-01-20T13:48:44.203" Title="How to write to Web.Config in Medium Trust?" Tags="&lt;c#&gt;&lt;asp.net&gt;&lt;medium-trust&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="1" FavoriteCount="2" />
  <row Id="580" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="586" CreationDate="2008-08-02T23:30:59.090" Score="26" ViewCount="6764" Body="&lt;p&gt;I wonder how you guys manage deployment of a database between 2 SQL Servers, specifically SQL Server 2005.&#xA;Now, there is a development and a live one. As this should be part of a buildscript (standard windows batch, even do with current complexity of those scripts, i might switch to PowerShell or so later), Enterprise Manager/Management Studio Express do not count.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Would you just copy the .mdf File and attach it? I am always a bit careful when working with binary data, as this seems to be a compatiblity issue (even though development and live should run the same version of the server at all time).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Or - given the lack of &quot;EXPLAIN CREATE TABLE&quot; in T-SQL - do you do something that exports an existing database into SQL-Scripts which you can run on the target server? If yes, is there a tool that can automatically dump a given Database into SQL Queries and that runs off the command line? (Again, Enterprise Manager/Management Studio Express do not count).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And lastly - given the fact that the live database already contains data, the deployment may not involve creating all tables but rather checking the difference in structure and ALTER TABLE the live ones instead, which may also need data verification/conversion when existing fields change.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now, i hear a lot of great stuff about the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.red-gate.com/products/index.htm&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Red Gate&lt;/a&gt; products, but for hobby projects, the price is a bit steep.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, what are you using to automatically deploy SQL Server Databases from Test to Live?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="91" LastEditorUserId="2641576" LastEditorDisplayName="Mark Harrison" LastEditDate="2014-11-25T20:58:47.550" LastActivityDate="2014-11-25T20:58:47.550" Title="Deploying SQL Server Databases from Test to Live" Tags="&lt;sql-server&gt;&lt;sql-server-2005&gt;&lt;deployment&gt;&lt;release-management&gt;" AnswerCount="14" CommentCount="0" FavoriteCount="5" />
  <row Id="585" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="580" CreationDate="2008-08-02T23:40:04.733" Score="13" Body="&lt;p&gt;For my projects I alternate between SQL Compare from REd Gate and the Database Publishing Wizard from Microsoft which you can download free&#xA;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?familyid=56E5B1C5-BF17-42E0-A410-371A838E570A&amp;amp;displaylang=en&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Wizard isn't as slick as SQL Compare or SQL Data Compare but it does the trick. One issue is that the scripts it generates may need some rearranging and/or editing to flow in one shot.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the up side, it can move your schema and data which isn't bad for a free tool.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="149" LastActivityDate="2008-08-02T23:40:04.733" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="633" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="588" CreationDate="2008-08-03T07:50:37.617" Score="21" Body="&lt;p&gt;I have not used PHP to do this but have experience in using C# to achieve the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Outlook API is a way of automating Outlook rather than connecting to Exchange directly. I have previously taken this approach in a C# application and it does work although can be buggy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you wish to connect directly to the Exchange server you will need to research extended MAPI.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the past I used this wrapper &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codeproject.com/KB/IP/CMapiEx.aspx&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;MAPIEx: Extended MAPI Wrapper&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is a C# project but I believe you can use some .NET code on a PHP5 Windows server. Alternatively it has a C++ core DLL that you may be a able to use. I have found it to be very good and there are some good example applications.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Update:&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sorry for the delay no current way to keep track of posts yet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I do agree adding more layer on to your application and relying on 3rd party code can be scary (and rightfully so.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today I read another &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/4508/mapi-and-managed-code-experiences&quot;&gt;interesting post&lt;/a&gt; tagged up as MAPI that is on a different subject. The key thing here though is that it has linked to &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.msdn.com/mstehle/archive/2007/10/03/fyi-why-are-mapi-and-cdo-1-21-not-supported-in-managed-net-code.aspx&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;this important MS article&lt;/a&gt;. I have been unaware of the issues until now on using managed code to interface to MAPI although the C++ code in the component should be unaffected by this error as it is unmanaged. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This blog entry also suggests other ways to connect to MAPI/Exchange server. In this case due to these new facts &lt;a href=&quot;http://us3.php.net/imap&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;http://us3.php.net/imap&lt;/a&gt; may be the answer as suggested by the other user.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="33" LastEditorUserId="-1" LastEditorDisplayName="user1873471" LastEditDate="2017-05-23T11:46:37.490" LastActivityDate="2013-01-27T11:35:54.863" CommentCount="0" />
</posts>